so first of all good morning thanks for
首先，早上好，谢谢
coming to this jax-rs and CDI bike
来这辆jax-rs和CDI自行车
directive bridge session
指令桥会议
so before we start and very quickly a
所以在我们开始之前，很快
few words about us so my name is David
关于我们的几句话，所以我叫大卫
Alaba C I work at Oracle in the
Alaba CI在Oracle的
organization that is responsible for
负责的组织
Java SE Java EE we are also responsible
Java SE Java EE我们也负责
for open source projects such as
适用于开源项目，例如
GlassFish Jersey our org is also
我们的组织也
responsible for commercial product such
负责此类商品
as WebLogic server and other cool stuff
作为WebLogic服务器和其他有趣的东西
like the event project that was just
就像只是一个活动项目
open source during the keynote before
在主题演讲之前开源
that I spent 10 years at Sun and before
我在Sun及之前呆了十年
Sun I spent four years working on Java
Sun我花了四年时间从事Java工作
so basically by looking at the evolution
所以基本上看一下进化
of my Orkut you can clearly see that
我的Orkut可以清楚地看到
I've been involved in the Java space
我参与了Java领域
since quite some times and my name is
因为好几次了，我的名字是
Josie I live in Paris area
乔西我住在巴黎地区
I provided here's some links what we're
我提供了一些链接，我们是
going to talk quite a lot about
将会谈论很多
completion stage and completable future
完成阶段和可完成的未来
and the interaction with the jax-rs API
以及与jax-rs API的交互
and if you check my youtube account I
如果您查看我的YouTube帐户，我
have several talks especially on the
有几个演讲，特别是关于
topic of the completion stage stuff I'm
我是完成阶段的主题
also on and also for our site and the
同样在我们的网站上
proud member of the Paris Java user
巴黎Java用户的骄傲成员
group
组
so this was me some months ago
所以几个月前就是我
a Jeff acoustic conference in Sweden
瑞典的Jeff声学会议
where I was giving a talk and someone in
我正在演讲的地方，有人在
the audience
听众
tweeted that it's not a real conference
推特说这不是一个真正的会议
unless you read or actor safe harbor
除非您阅读或演员安全港
statement at least once so please enjoy
声明至少一次，请欣赏
now today we're going to talk about
今天我们要谈的是
future but future as in the concurrent
未来，但同时发生
util package not future as in future
util软件包不像将来那样
stuff that we might do in a product so
我们可能会在产品中做的事情
we're on the safe side
我们站在安全的一面
so we can basically ignore what is being
所以我们基本上可以忽略正在发生的事情
said there next is our personal
说接下来是我们的个人
disclaimer the on French it's much much
在法语上免责声明
easier than others understanding French
比其他人更容易理解法语
speaking English now I'm not French but
现在说英语，我不是法语，但
don't tell Josie so let first set the
不要告诉乔西，让我们先设置
stage so today we're going to talk about
舞台，所以今天我们要谈论
reactive now if you look at directive
如果您查看指令，现在就反应
manifestos it defines things like
宣言定义了类似的东西
elasticity like responsiveness
像反应一样的弹性
I think message passing those kind of
我认为消息传递了那种
things by reactive in the context of
在...的情况下通过反应
this presentation we really mean
这个演讲，我们的意思是
reactive as the ability to respond
反应能力
efficiently to some kind of event that
有效地应对某种事件
are passed so basically we will take
通过了，所以基本上我们会采取
some of the API that are part of the
部分API的一部分
Java platform like Jack's arrest and CDI
Java平台，例如Jack的逮捕和CDI
too and we will kind of extract them
同样，我们将提取它们
from Java and we will use them in a pure
从Java，我们将在纯
Java C context having said that all the
Java C上下文说明了所有
patterns that we're going to present
我们将要呈现的模式
today will also perfectly work in a pure
今天也可以完美地工作
Java environment and the idea is really
Java环境和想法真的
to look on how we can leverage those API
看看我们如何利用这些API
and the Java EE compression stage API to
和Java EE压缩阶段API来
basically have this reactive had this
基本上有这个反应
reactive capacity to your to your
对您的反应能力
application and once you will get the
应用程序，一旦您将获得
parents that we will present once you
父母，一旦您，我们将介绍
will apply those patterns to your
将这些模式应用于您的
application at the end of the day your
在一天结束时申请
application will exist obviously be
应用程序显然将存在
using a synchronous message passing
使用同步消息传递
capabilities but at the end of the day
功能，但归根结底
they will scale more and they will be
他们将扩大规模，他们将
more responsive so that's really what we
反应更快，这就是我们真正的
mean by reactive today
意思是今天反应
so the first API that I want to discuss
所以我要讨论的第一个API
is the jax-rs API we'll spend a fair bit
是jax-rs API，我们将花一些钱
of time on jax-rs because basically our
时间在jax-rs上，因为基本上
session is based on how we can better
会议基于我们如何更好
use Jack's address using this hi this
使用这个的杰克的地址
reactive ID so we have just released
反应性ID，所以我们刚刚发布了
Jack's rs21
杰克的rs21
along with Java 8 Jack's rest one comes
连同Java 8 Jack的其余一款一起来
with different enhancements like support
具有不同的增强功能，例如支持
for service and even support for Jason B
为Jason B提供服务甚至支持
and so on and so on we're gonna we
等等等等，我们要
basically will skip that today we will
基本上今天我们会跳过
focus on one specific feature that has
专注于一项具有
been added in Jack's rs21
已添加到杰克的rs21中
and that is a new reactive invoker so to
这是一个新的反应式调用程序，因此
explain what the what that reactive
解释什么是什么反应
invoker solve let's first look at the
调用者解决让我们先来看一下
jax-rs client API that we have inject
我们注入的jax-rs客户端API
the rest - so injector is - we basically
其余的-喷油器是-我们基本上
have an API that we can use to easily
有一个我们可以轻松使用的API
consume a remote rest endpoint and the
消耗远程休息端点，并且
way it work well first you need to have
首先需要它如何运作良好
a client object so that's basically a
客户对象，因此基本上是
client-side container that you can use
您可以使用的客户端容器
to consume remote endpoint you get it
使用远程端点就可以了
through this method called so client
通过这种叫做so client的方法
will learn the client and you will get
将学习客户，您将获得
that kind container it's convention over
那种容器就过去了
configuration
组态
I haven't specify anything but obviously
我没有指定任何东西，但显然
I have the ability to configure that if
我有能力配置，如果
I need to once I have my client
我需要我的客户
container I need to construct a web
我需要建立一个网站的容器
target a web target is bar basically
瞄准网页目标基本上是酒吧
some kind of glorified URL so it's
某种美化的网址，因此
basically where on the network is more
基本上在网络上更多的地方
remote rest endpoint I have my web
远程休息端点，我有我的网站
target so next I need to construct based
目标，所以接下来我需要构建基于
on my target my request so that's
在我的目标我的要求，所以
basically the request that I would like
基本上我想要的要求
my client-side container to issue and
我的客户端容器发出和
then we see at some point in time I will
然后我们会在某个时间点看到
issue that request so basically I will
发出该请求，所以基本上我会
tell my client container to issue that
告诉我的客户容器发出
rest request so in this case for example
休息请求，因此在这种情况下，例如
we see that this is a get request it
我们看到这是一个获取请求
could be a post request it could be a
可能是发布请求，可能是
delete request it doesn't really matter
删除请求并不重要
and you see that what we are expecting
您会看到我们所期待的
to get in return is a return is a
得到回报是回报是
forecast object
预测对象
and given that we have this kind
鉴于我们有这种
container that we can use multiple time
我们可以多次使用的容器
obviously we need to make sure that we
显然，我们需要确保我们
close it it implemented to close every
关闭它实现关闭每个
interface so that's one easy way to deal
界面，这是一种简单的交易方式
with that concern
带着这种担忧
so in jax-rs 2 we have discount API we
所以在jax-rs 2中，我们有折扣API
have this fluent API you get the plan
拥有这个流利的API，您可以计划
builder from the client builder who you
来自客户端构建器的构建器，您是谁
get a client from the client you said
从你说的客户那里得到一个客户
the web target from the web target
网络目标中的网络目标
consumer request and finally you invoke
消费者请求，最后您调用
the request bail response now if you
如果您现在要求保释
look at the bottom of the slides we have
看看我们的幻灯片的底部
a typical request so we have the ability
一个典型的要求，所以我们有能力
to set the headers and so on it doesn't
设置标题等等
really matter but what is key here is
真的很重要，但是关键是
the fact that the gate is blocking so
大门被堵的事实
the kind container will issue the
那种容器会发出
request and basically my method will
请求，基本上我的方法会
block until we get the result from the
阻止，直到我们从
remote end point now in jax-rs 2 we also
现在在jax-rs 2中的远程端点
have a synchronous capabilities so if
具有同步功能，如果
you don't specify anything that will be
您没有指定任何会
a blocking request so asynchronous
如此异步的阻止请求
request but if you look at the bottom of
请求，但如果您查看的底部
the slide I have this a sync method so
幻灯片中有一个同步方法
this is basically to tell to the jacks
这基本上是告诉插孔
rest and container that I want to use
我要使用的休息和容器
the assignment worker and if you look at
任务工，如果你看
the return type of that request
该请求的返回类型
invocation we don't have a string
调用我们没有字符串
anymore in this in this case but we have
在这种情况下，但是我们有
a future of string so the basically
字符串的未来，所以基本上
means that we have an object that we can
意味着我们有一个可以
use in the future to basically get the
将来用于基本获得
result from the request invocation
请求调用的结果
now if we if we do those that kind of
现在，如果我们这样做的话
request we will answer we will basically
要求我们将回答我们将基本上
have a non-blocking code so our method
有非阻塞代码，所以我们的方法
will return right after the get right
正确后将立即返回
but you know that to access a future
但你知道进入未来
object we need to do a get and the issue
我们需要获取的对象和问题
is that that gate is blocking so with
是那个门被挡住了
that we haven't sold anything we have
我们没有卖任何东西
just delayed a problem we still have a
只是推迟了一个问题，我们仍然有一个
blocking behavior and obviously we don't
阻止行为，显然我们没有
really want that the issue is that if it
真正想要的问题是，如果它
takes forever for the remote endpoint to
永远需要远程端点
send a result well our code will be
发送好结果，我们的代码将是
blocked forever so what you need to make
永远被封锁，所以你需要做什么
sure is you need to make sure that you
确定是您需要确保您
at least have a timeout right so if it
至少有超时的权利，所以如果
takes more than 5 seconds in this case
在这种情况下需要5秒钟以上
we'll have an exception so our code will
我们会有一个例外，因此我们的代码将
be blocked at word for 5 seconds which
被字挡了5秒钟
is not ideal but it's better than it be
不理想，但比它更好
hanged forever now we can also do these
永远吊死现在我们也可以做这些
kind of things so instead of directly
所以不是直接
accessing the future object we can check
访问我们可以检查的未来对象
if there is some reason in that object
如果那个物体有某种原因
and if there is we can access it so it
如果有我们可以访问它
it doesn't really solve the issue
并不能真正解决问题
and what you also need to make sure is
而且您还需要确保
that you set some timer but now a judge
你设置了一个计时器但现在是法官
access level to make sure that again if
访问级别，以确保再次
for some reason you don't get a response
由于某种原因，您没有得到回应
from the remote endpoint your code is
从远程端点，您的代码是
not hanged forever now the good news is
现在不是永远吊死的好消息是
is that in Jack's arrest two we have a
是在杰克的逮捕中，我们有一个
facility that allows us to basically
可以让我们基本上
work around those blocking issue and
解决这些阻塞问题，并
that's an invocation callback facilities
这是调用回调工具
so it's basically an interface that has
所以基本上是一个具有
two method that need to be implemented
需要实现的两种方法
completed and failed and the name are
完成并失败，名称为
pretty obvious
很明显
so the completed callback will basically
因此完成的回调基本上
be invoked when we have the result from
当我们得到以下结果时被调用
the remote endpoint and failed will be
远程端点并失败了
invoked if something goes wrong so it
如果出了问题就调用它
works like this so I'm still so this is
像这样工作，所以我还是这样
a normal jack service request using the
使用
asset invoker
资产调用者
to tell to my client container that this
告诉我的客户容器
is indeed a distinct invocation and now
确实是一个独特的调用，现在
when I do the request I pass it an
当我执行请求时，我将其传递给
invocation callback
调用回调
invocation callback that needs to have
需要具有的调用回调
two callbacks completed to deal with the
完成了两个回调以处理
response that will be signed at some
将在某些时候签署的回应
point in time by the remote endpoint and
远程端点的时间点
fail if something goes wrong now let's
如果出了问题会失败，现在让我们
put that into perspective so this is a
透视一下，这是一个
typical micro-services scenario where we
我们在典型的微服务场景中
have one travel agency services that
有一个旅行社服务
need to consume multiple back-end
需要消耗多个后端
services in this case we have four
在这种情况下，我们有四个服务
back-end services and the idea of the
后端服务和
scenario is that we have a user that
场景是我们有一个用户
comes in the travel and gentle services
出差旅行和周到的服务
will invoke the customer services to get
将调用客户服务以获取
the history of that users once we have
用户拥有的历史
that we will invoke the destination to
我们将调用目标
have a potential destination that we can
有一个我们可以的潜在目的地
suggest to that user based on its travel
根据其旅行向该用户建议
history and for each destination that
历史以及每个目的地
we're about to suggest we would not like
我们将建议我们不要
to have some weather information and
有一些天气信息和
some coding information so the user
一些编码信息，以便用户
comes in and travel agency services will
进来，旅行社服务将
be the client of those four back-end
成为这四个后端的客户
services and it has to answer with like
服务，它必须像回答
five or ten destination with all the
五个或十个目的地
details like forecast and pricing for
详细信息，例如预测和定价
the given users now
现在给定的用户
this is pretty obvious but if we put
这是很明显的，但是如果我们把
some cost on some cost on some weight on
一些成本，一些重量，
the request invocation that we have to
我们必须执行的请求调用
do we clearly see that if we go through
我们是否清楚地看到，如果我们经历
a pure blocking serial approach it
纯阻塞串行方法
doesn't make sense it will take like
没有道理，它将需要
five seconds to return those results so
五秒钟返回这些结果，所以
we clearly that scale is not something
我们清楚地知道规模不是问题
that we want to do on the other hand we
另一方面，我们想做的是
see that we can optimize our
看到我们可以优化我们的
orchestration workflow between those
那些之间的业务流程
different services invocation so for
不同的服务调用
example the first services that we need
示例我们需要的第一个服务
to invoke is the customer little
调用的客户很少
services once we have that we have to
服务，一旦我们有，我们必须
invoke the recommendation destination
调用推荐目的地
services but once we have the
服务，但是一旦我们有了
destination to suggest we can invoke in
建议我们可以调用的目的地
parallel the quoting services for that
与此并行的报价服务
given destination and the weather
给定目的地和天气
forecast for that same given destination
预测相同目的地
so if we applied again the cost of those
因此，如果我们再次应用这些费用
requests we see that at the end of the
要求我们在末尾看到
day we should have something that is way
一天，我们应该拥有某种方式
faster now let's look on how it can work
现在更快，让我们看看它如何工作
with the jax-rs
与jax-rs
to API and with this invocation callback
API并使用此调用回调
facility and let's simplify the scenario
工具，让我们简化方案
a little bit let's just pretend that we
让我们假装一点
have only two service system consume the
只有两个服务系统消耗
destination services and the weather
目的地服务和天气
services so how we would write that code
服务，那么我们如何编写该代码
using the jax-rs two api we have a first
使用jax-rs两个api我们有一个
request that buzz if you get the
要求获得嗡嗡声
destination the recommended destination
推荐目的地
it's an a sync request right given it's
鉴于它是一个同步请求
in a sync request we have to pass it an
在同步请求中，我们必须将其传递给
invocation callback an invocation
调用回调
callback has to call back the completed
回调必须回调完成
that's the callback that will be invoked
那就是将被调用的回调
when we have the result so when we have
当我们有结果时
the destination what are we what are we
目的地我们是什么我们是什么
doing well we'll basically go over all
做得好，我们基本上会研究所有
the distinction that we have and for its
我们拥有的区别
destination we will do another request
目的地，我们将再次提出要求
another rest request it will be nothing
另一个休息的请求将一无所获
requests so that mean that we have to
请求，这意味着我们必须
pass it an invocation callback
向其传递调用回调
invocation callback with to call back
调用回调与回调
including the completed that will deal
包括完成的交易
with the result so in this case we just
结果，在这种情况下，我们只是
get the forecast information from the
从中获取预测信息
remote endpoint and we had it to a map
远程端点，我们将其放置到地图上
for that given destination
对于给定的目的地
and obviously we have to implement the
显然，我们必须实施
fail callback for the two type of
两种类型的失败回调
requests that we have so I guess that
要求我们有，所以我想
you want you well you see where I'm
你想要你很好，你知道我在哪里
going to this is basically going to be a
基本上这将是一个
callback hell and I had to simplify my
回调地狱，我不得不简化我的
scenario to two services just to try to
方案到两个服务只是为了尝试
make it fit on to slide the original
使它适合滑动原件
basic scenario had four services so that
基本方案有四个服务，因此
kind that kind of code is difficult to
那种代码很难
write debug and maintain so clearly it's
编写调试并维护得非常清楚
not something that will work over time
不会随着时间的推移而起作用
and that's the issue when you have
这就是当你有
services with dependency so the good
有依赖性的服务，所以很好
news is that and that's the point of
新闻是，这就是重点
this talk in Jack's rs21 we have a new
在Jack的rs21的演讲中，我们有了一个新的
reactive invoker so you see at the
反应性调用程序，因此您可以在
bottom of the slide we have this rx
幻灯片的底部，我们有这个RX
method that is basically used to tell to
基本上用来告诉的方法
the jax-rs kind container that we want
我们想要的jax-rs类容器
to use an a synchronous reactive invoker
使用同步反应式调用程序
and if you look at the return type of
如果您查看的返回类型
that invoker it's not a future object
那个调用者不是未来的对象
anymore
不再
it's a completion stage of the response
这是回应的完成阶段
type the main difference between the
键入之间的主要区别
future and the completion stage stuff is
未来和完成阶段的东西是
that the completion stage a Java 8 so
Java 8这样的完成阶段
it's kind of modern API where's the
这是一种现代的API，
future stuff in Java 5 2004 so it's
Java 5 2004中的未来内容
almost a very it's an older API and so
几乎是一个较旧的API，因此
far completion stage is an interface
完成阶段是一个界面
implemented by computable future it's a
由可计算的未来实现，这是一个
full API the idea is really to to take a
完整的API的想法实际上是采取
task and this task is going to be
任务，这个任务将是
modeled as a lambda since we are in the
由于我们位于
Java 8 welder and this card task is
Java 8焊机，此卡任务为
going to be executed as synchronously in
将被同步执行
another thread than the calling thread
除调用线程外的另一个线程
by default we can pass an executor
默认情况下，我们可以通过执行程序
service by the way to tell the API hey
服务的方式告诉API嘿
you should be executing this task in
您应该在执行此任务
this given executor service or in this a
这个给定的执行人服务，或者这个
given given thread the nice thing is
给定线程的好处是
that given a completion stage having the
给出了具有
responsibility to execute a task we can
执行任务的责任
chain other tasks on it that are going
链接正在进行的其他任务
to be executed on the completion of this
在此完成时执行
completion stage which is not the case
完成阶段不是这样
with the future API you you we cannot do
使用未来的API，您将无法做到
that in the future API so the idea is
在未来的API中，这个想法是
really to create the chain of a
真正打造一个
synchronous task here CS wanna which is
同步任务在这里CS想
my first completion stage that will
我的第一个完成阶段
trigger two for the tasks 21 and 22 then
触发两个任务21和22然后
22 does not trigger anything 21 triggers
22不触发任何东西21触发器
31 and on the other side I also have
31在另一边，我也有
another task independent of those as yes
与任务无关的另一个任务是
32 and both 31 and 32 are going once
32，而31和32都将运行一次
they are both completed are going to
他们都完成了
trigger CS 41 so this is basically the
触发CS 41，所以这基本上是
kind of graph of tasks I can create
我可以创建的任务图
using this completion stage API this is
使用此完成阶段API，这是
the big picture now
现在的大局
this completion stage API is quite
这个完成阶段的API相当
complex there are a lot of methods in it
复杂其中有很多方法
also a lot of methods in the completable
也有很多方法可以完成
future stuff it's a bit it's a bit
未来的东西有点
cluttered to to understands not easy to
凌乱地去理解不容易
understand it at first what are going to
首先了解它会做什么
do what we're going to do here is really
做我们在这里要做的事情真的是
to to present the simple pattern to
将简单的模式呈现给
solve the problem that we have set up
解决我们已经建立的问题
with David that is triggering queries on
与David一起触发查询
red services given the list of
红色服务给出的清单
destinations we have so let's go first
我们有目的地，让我们先走
the first step is to query the the
第一步是查询
forecast backend service once we have
一旦有了我们就可以预测后端服务
the the list of destinations remember we
目的地清单请记住我们
are customer we are buying some kind of
是客户，我们正在购买某种
travel somewhere and and the website
旅行到某个地方和网站
we're on wants to push us other
我们正在想把我们推向其他
destination that we may be interested in
我们可能感兴趣的目的地
and along with those destination we want
以及我们想要的目的地
to add to information the forecast for
向信息添加预测
this destination and a quotation of
此目的地和报价
price for that destination and
该目的地的价格和
everything is distributed among several
一切都分布在几个
rest services so given given a
休息服务因此给定了
destination unknown destination the
目的地不明目的地
first thing I can I can do is query the
我能做的第一件事就是查询
forecast service using this kind of
使用这种预测服务
pattern most of the time this since it
此后大部分时间都在
is a red service what I will be getting
是一项红色的服务，我将得到
is in fact a JSON object so once I have
实际上是一个JSON对象，所以一旦我有了
this JSON object sometime in the future
将来某个时间此JSON对象
remember this is a completion stage what
还记得这是完成阶段么
I can do is what I must do sorry is ill
我能做的是我必须做的对不起病了
modulate using some basic JSON builder
使用一些基本的JSON构建器进行调制
code
码
just like this so this is a function
就像这样，这是一个功能
that is just taking a JSON object and
那只是一个JSON对象，
marshaling into into a forecast object
编组成为预测对象
that data get that I can use right so
得到的数据我可以正确使用
how can i trigger the execution of this
我该如何触发执行
function once this completion stage is
一旦完成阶段就开始运作
completed well I have an API for that
完成得很好，我有一个API
query forecast this is my completion
查询预测这是我的完成
state object then apply a Marshall
状态对象然后应用马歇尔
forecast the this will trigger this then
预测这将触发此
apply trigger method method call will
应用触发方法方法调用将
trigger the own marshaling of the JSON
触发自己的JSON封送处理
object once it is available that is
对象一旦可用即为
sometimes in the future all right so I
有时候将来还可以，所以我
need to rub that into a method that
需要把它揉成一种方法
takes a destination this destination
到达目的地
will first trigger a request on a
首先会触发一个请求
forecast
预测
res server that will return a JSON
将返回JSON的res服务器
object this JSON object will be earned
对象将获得此JSON对象
my child by the the unemotional forecast
我孩子的情绪低落
object and then once I have this
对象，然后一旦我有这个
forecast object the idea is to set a
预测对象的想法是设置一个
special property of my destination
我目的地的特殊财产
object with this forecast object thus
对象与此预测对象因此
making this forecast available directly
直接提供此预测
in my destination bin so basically this
在我的目的地箱中，所以基本上
takes a destination object and does not
接受目标对象，但不接受
do much with it it does not return a new
用它做很多事情不会返回新的
destination object it just set a
目标对象，它只是设置一个
property inside this destination object
此目标对象内的属性
so this is a function that takes the
所以这是一个需要
destination object and since there is a
目标对象，因为有一个
then apply that is the triggering of the
然后应用那是触发
own marshalling and then except that is
自己编组，然后是
the triggering of the setting of the
触发设置
property inside the object it returns a
对象内部的属性返回一个
completion stage avoid the building of
完成阶段避免建设
this function doesn't do anything it's
这个功能什么也没做
just a declaration of some kind of
只是某种声明
methods in a pipeline so it's a it
管道中的方法，所以
returns immediately but of course the
立即返回，但当然
the task itself will be executed at some
任务本身将在某个时间执行
time in the future so once I have that I
未来的时间，所以一旦我有了我
can do the same with quotation for
可以做同样的报价
instance following the exact same
实例完全一样
pattern so if I have like three or four
模式，如果我有三个或四个
property to set in my destination object
在我的目标对象中设置的属性
querying three or four rest services
查询三个或四个休息服务
corresponding read services I can
我可以相应的阅读服务
multiply this
乘以这个
number of functions this returned a
返回的功能数量
competition stage of void and this is
竞争阶段无效，这是
what I am going to use in the future so
我将来会用什么
what does my travel service will begin
我的旅行服务将开始什么？
to look like I have I can create this
看起来像我可以创建这个
populate destination function that
填充目标函数
basically takes a destination and will
基本上会到达目的地
set the different properties of this
设置这个的不同属性
destination object using the result of
目标对象使用的结果
the querying of the rest services for
其余服务的查询
that I am going to use this static
我将要使用此静态
method from the completable future a
未来完成方法
class compatible future all of that
类兼容的未来
returns a completion stage that can that
返回完成阶段，可以
again make as they can that again get as
尽他们所能再次获得
a computable future using the two
两者结合的可计算的未来
computable future method then this
那么可计算的未来方法
completion state object this olaf object
完成状态对象此olaf对象
will be completed wants all the past
将要过去的一切完成
completion stage are going to be
完成阶段将是
completed themselves so if i have three
完成自己，所以如果我有三个
four or more property to set up all i
四个或更多财产来设置所有我
need to do is just scale this pattern by
需要做的只是按比例缩放此模式
passing more completion stage to this
通过更多的完成阶段
olaf method which is something i can do
我可以做的奥拉夫方法
now the nice thing is that if I have
现在的好处是，如果我有
many threads in my executor service that
我的执行器服务中有很多线程
is going to execute that all those
将要执行所有这些
requests are going to be executed in
请求将在
parallel
平行
suppose I have 50 properties to set up
假设我要设置50个属性
if I have 25 threads then every thread
如果我有25个线程，那么每个线程
will handle probably two properties to
将处理可能的两个属性
set up but if I have more than 50
设置但如果我有50个以上
threads every every query and properly
正确处理每个查询
set up will be handled in it's given
设置将在给定的条件下处理
thread thus making things much faster as
从而使事情变得更快
David showed in the in the in the big
大卫在大片中展示了
picture image about the the the
关于的图片
organization of the of the of the
的组织
overall system so this is something that
整个系统，所以这是
takes to destination and will populate
到达目的地并将填充
the properties of that destination using
使用该目的地的属性
the querying of the rest services in an
其余服务的查询
a synchronous way and in a parallel way
同步方式和并行方式
right so this destination now I need to
对，所以现在我要去这个目的地
get it from somewhere so let us do that
从某处获取它，让我们这样做
what I get in fact from the from the res
我实际上从res那里得到什么
service from the first read service is
来自第一个读取服务的服务是
list of destination so what I need to do
目的地列表，所以我需要做什么
now is for each of those destination
现在是针对每个目的地
apply this function one by one now this
现在一个接一个地应用此功能
is of course the nice job for the stream
当然对流来说是不错的工作
API so I can just stream this list of
API，因此我可以流式传输此列表
destination for each destination apply
每个目的地适用的目的地
this populate destination function that
这个填充目标函数
will return a compatible future that
将返回兼容的未来
will complete once all the properties of
一旦完成所有属性
that precise destination are going to be
确切的目的地将是
set up all right so I have in this
设置好吧，所以我在这
stream here I have one compatible future
在这里流，我有一个兼容的未来
/ destination each compatible future
/目的地各兼容的未来
corresponding to as many comparable
对应尽可能多的可比性
future I have four properties I need to
未来我需要四个属性
set ok so that may be a lot really if I
设置好，所以如果我真的会很多
have 50 destination and three properties
有50个目的地和三个属性
to set that will be a hundred and fifty
设置为一百五十
a comparable future in the end and I'm
最后的可比未来，我
going to put all this computable feature
将把所有这些可计算的功能
in an array why because what I'm
在一个数组中为什么因为我是
interested in is the time at which all
感兴趣的是所有的时间
those completable future will complete
那些可以完成的未来将会完成
and for that I'm going to to use an Olaf
为此，我将使用奥拉夫
static call once again and for that I
静态调用再次为此
need an array so I'm going to put all
需要一个数组，所以我要把所有
the results of this of this stream
此流的结果
mapping in an array okay so how can I
在数组中映射好，那我该如何
set up that now in my rest service
现在在我的休息服务中进行设置
objects RS I have two patterns in fact
对象RS我实际上有两种模式
that first popular destination that
第一个受欢迎的目的地
returns a void and takes an a sink
返回一个空白并接收一个接收器
response and this is a jax-rs 2.0
响应，这是一个jax-rs 2.0
pattern I first query my destination red
模式我首先查询目的地红色
service that is going to return me a
服务将返回我一个
list of destination after some JSON be
JSON后的目标列表
and marshaling of my JSON array object
和封送我的JSON数组对象
we'll leave that aside then I can get my
我们将其放在一边，然后我可以拿到我的
completion stage by composing this
通过组成这个完成阶段
destined is this completion stage that
注定是这个完成阶段
will get the list of destination with
将获得目的地的列表
the function I just wrote in a previous
我之前写的函数
slide right using the Zen compost and
使用Zen堆肥向右滑动，然后
the Olaf remember that this popular
奥拉夫记得
destination returns itself an array okay
目的地返回自己一个数组好吗
so this computable future Olaf will be
所以这个可计算的未来奥拉夫将是
completed once all the destinations have
一旦所有目的地都完成
been populated with their properties I
被他们的属性填充
want to set this returns an updated
想要设置此返回更新
destination
目的地
a completion stage and I need to pass
完成阶段，我需要通过
the payload of this completion stage to
完成阶段的有效负载为
the a sync response because this is the
同步响应，因为这是
way this this pattern works in jax-rs
这种模式在jax-rs中的工作方式
2.0 so I need to switch this completion
2.0，所以我需要切换此完成
stage into a compatible future and since
进入兼容的未来
compatible future is an extension of a
兼容的未来是对
future I can call the get method with
将来我可以调用get方法
all the precautions that David told
大卫告诉我的所有注意事项
showed you time outs and stuff like that
告诉你超时和类似的东西
if the process takes too long now this
如果这个过程花了太长时间
is I would say the old-fashioned way of
我会说老式的方式
writing things since I am in and jax-rs
因为我在和jax-rs而写东西
2.1 well I can also directly return this
2.1好，我也可以直接返回
completion stage and the opening of this
完成阶段和开幕
completion stage will be handled by the
完成阶段将由
jax-rs 2.1 API directly all right so
jax-rs 2.1 API直接就可以了
this is the big picture on I would say a
这是大图，我会说
real world example on a non trivial
一个不平凡的现实世界的例子
example to handle the this completion
处理此完成的示例
stage API now what is happening if I
阶段API现在如果我发生了什么
have an exception at some point I am
我有些时候有例外
querying red services they might not be
查询可能不是的红色服务
here I am and maturing some JSON objects
在这里，我正在成熟一些JSON对象
this could raise exceptions the idea in
这可能会引发例外情况
the completion stage API is that if at a
完成阶段的API是
given point of my chain of tasks an
给定我的任务链的重点
exception is raised then all the
引发异常，然后所有
downstreams completion stage will be
下游完成阶段将是
also raised an exception so it will it
也提出了一个例外，它将
will kind of break all the process if I
如果我会破坏所有过程
have an exception at some point but I
在某个时候有例外，但我
have methods to handle that which is
有方法来处理
nice the first one I have is the
不错，我的第一个是
exceptional a method that returns a new
异常返回新值的方法
completion stage and I can decide if
完成阶段，我可以决定是否
this completion stage is in error itself
这个完成阶段本身就是错误的
or not using that okay so let us try to
或不使用该行，让我们尝试
do something smart with exceptions I
做一些例外的聪明事
know it's not easy but hey we can at
知道这并不容易，但是我们可以
least try I also have a handle method
最少尝试我也有一个handle方法
that takes both the result and the
这需要结果和
exception if there is no exception then
如果没有例外，那么例外
this exception object will be new and if
此异常对象将是新的，如果
it's not the case there will be
并非如此
something with it so I can decide to
有一些东西，所以我可以决定
create a new result for instance that is
创建一个新的结果，例如
a that is near for instance if I do not
例如，如果我不靠近
have the forecast and I can live with
有预测，我可以忍受
that with no information on the
没有关于的信息
Podcast I can just call the set forecast
播客我可以叫设定的预报
with the new object I could decide to do
与新的对象，我可以决定做
that and I also went complete method
那我也去了完整的方法
that instead of a bit of a B function
而不是一点B功能
takes a big consumer that will not
需要一个不会
return anything and that is another way
返回任何东西，那是另一种方式
of handling exceptions so so in fact
处理异常的事实
I've got three ways of handling
我有三种处理方式
exceptions with the completion stage API
完成阶段API的异常
so here is what it's going to do here is
所以这是这里要做的
the the the pattern we just wrote we
我们刚刚写的模式
apply the the it until the young
应用它直到年轻
Marshall quotation for instance object
实例对象的马歇尔报价
suppose we have an exception all right
假设我们有一个例外
we could say all right we got an
我们可以说好吧，我们得到了
exception so we take it with this
例外，所以我们对此
exceptionally method if there is no
如果没有，则为异常方法
exception this exceptionally call will
例外，此异常调用将
not do anything so just be transparent
什么也没做，所以要透明
in the China and decide in fact that if
在中国，事实上，如果
an exception is raised well it's not too
提出了一个例外，事实并非如此
bad the quotation will be new for this
不好的报价为此
object so I can still set a new value
对象，因此我仍然可以设置新值
for the property quotation of my
为我的财产报价
destination and this time my completion
目的地，这次是我的完成
stage will not be in error anymore
阶段将不会再有错误
thanks to the use of this exceptionally
多亏了这个的使用
method I could also decide to use the
我也可以决定使用
Andal method the pattern is not not that
安达法的模式不是那样
nice because I've got this if-then-else
很好，因为我有这个if-then-else
in it and since I am in a world of
在其中，因为我处在一个
lambdas and functional programming the
lambda和函数式编程
if then it doesn't really fit very well
如果那真的不太适合
in this world I think but hey you can
我想在这个世界上，但是嘿，你可以
still use it if you if you like it so if
如果您愿意，仍然可以使用它，如果
throwball is nearly it means that i do
投掷球几乎意味着我
not have any exception so i can just set
没有任何例外，所以我可以设置
the quotation like that if it is null
如果为空，则使用这样的引号
and I decide not to do well I will need
我决定做不好，我需要
to make a decision on what to do with
决定如何处理
this destination object all right
这个目标对象可以
[Music]
[音乐]
okay so you've saw some examples using
好的，所以您已经看到了一些使用示例
the new rx invoker that is now part of
现在是新的rx调用程序的一部分
Jax rs21 you saw that for all our
Jax rs21您已经为我们所有人看到了
example we have been using the HTTP GET
示例我们一直在使用HTTP GET
method but if it works for all the HTTP
方法，但如果它适用于所有HTTP
methods which are supported by the
所支持的方法
client API objects arise - 1 so that's
客户端API对象出现-1就是
delete get head option and so on so
删除获取头像选项，依此类推
basically all the HTTP methods but patch
基本上所有的HTTP方法，除了补丁
because patch is not supported by the
因为补丁不支持
client API now so what we have discussed
客户端API现在，我们已经讨论了什么
today is also how you can basically
今天基本上也可以
leverage access to one with the
利用
compression stooge API which is part of
压缩存储API是其中的一部分
the java SE 8 now we also acknowledge
Java SE 8现在我们也承认
that there are other reactive api in the
在其中还有其他反应式API
market so the jax-rs to one
市场使jax-rs成为一体
specification has been written in a way
规范以某种方式编写
so that in I mean it's it's mandatory to
因此，这是强制性的
support the completions the API but it's
支持补全API，但是
also open to third party API so any
同时也开放给第三方API
jax-rs implementer can decide to support
jax-rs实现者可以决定支持
in addition to the compression stage api
除了压缩阶段的api
autoreactive api and if you look at
自动反应式API，如果您看
Jersey which is the jax-rs to one well
新泽西州的一口井的球衣
which is the jax-rs reference
jax-rs参考
implementation we do support obviously
我们确实支持的实施
the compression stage that's something
压缩阶段
that we have to but we also support the
我们必须做到的，但我们也支持
guava stable future and we also support
番石榴稳定的未来，我们也支持
our in Java and our Java 2 so the weight
我们在Java和Java 2中的分量
work so if you want to use let's say for
工作，所以如果您想使用
example the flow bubble you first have
您首先遇到的气泡示例
when you construct your client container
当您构建客户端容器时
you need to pass it a specific invoker
您需要将特定的调用程序传递给它
provider for that API in this case it's
在这种情况下，该API的提供者是
our explorable invoker provider so you
我们可利用的调用方提供程序，因此您
pass it that class and then when you do
通过那堂课，然后当你做
the request you need to pass that
您需要通过的请求
specific invoker to using the rx method
使用rx方法的特定调用程序
and there we go you can then use that
然后我们就可以使用
specific reactive API so basically we
特定的反应式API，所以基本上
could use the pattern that we have
可以使用我们拥有的模式
discussed today with the compressions
今天讨论的压缩
that tej API but you can also use that
该tej API，但您也可以使用该API
way of thinking but using the specific
思维方式，但使用具体
reactive API that are in the market
市场上的反应式API
again this is optional but that's
再次，这是可选的，但这是
something that we do enjoy
我们喜欢的东西
now let's quickly quickly talk about CDI
现在让我们快速快速地谈论CDI
I mean what's the link between jax-rs
我的意思是jax-rs之间有什么联系
and CDI well in Java 8 we have released
我们已经发布了Java 8中的CDI和CDI
the CDI GSR three seven three six five
CDI GSR三七三六五
and well CDI two is addressing quite a
而CDI的两个解决方案
lot of new is having quite a lot of new
很多新事物有很多新事物
stuff but one of the things that CDI two
东西，但CDI的东西之一
is adding is a synchronous event so you
正在添加是一个同步事件，所以您
know that in CDI we have since the
知道在CDI中，我们自
beginning the this nice seven mechanism
开始这个很好的七种机制
so you have this producer consumer
所以你有这个生产者的消费者
patterns implementation that basically
基本实现的模式
allows you to easily produce event in
让您轻松产生事件
your application that would be consumed
您的应用程序将被消耗
somewhere I somewhere else in Europe in
我在欧洲其他地方的某个地方
your application the thing is that until
您的应用程序的问题是，直到
CDI - that was purely a synchronous so
CDI-纯粹是同步的
basically you were consuming the event
基本上你是在消耗事件
in the same trend as the producing
与生产趋势相同
thread this is not true anymore in CDI -
线程这在CDI中不再是真的-
so we now have the ability to raise and
所以我们现在有能力提高和
consume a synchronous event so the way
消耗一个同步事件，这样
it works it works exactly the same way
它的工作原理完全一样
so we are injecting an event of a given
所以我们注入给定的事件
type and then in Syria well if it would
输入，然后在叙利亚很好地输入
have been a synchronous event we would
一直是同步事件，我们会
have invoked on that event the fair
在那个事件上调用了公平
method if given that it's a NASA event
如果给出的是NASA事件，则该方法
we are invoking the fire async method so
我们正在调用fire异步方法，因此
it's a new method in CDI - so this is
这是CDI中的新方法-所以这是
the producing side so basically I'm
生产方面，所以基本上我是
producing an event here and obviously at
在这里，显然在
somewhere else I would like I will want
我想要的其他地方
to consume that event to consume that
消耗那个事件来消耗那个
event I just have to define an act
我只需要定义一个行为
nothing observable so for that I have a
没有什么可观察的，所以我有一个
method that is using this new at
正在使用此新方法的方法
observed a sync annotation and at
观察到同步注释，并在
anytime
任何时候
my an event will be fired but by that
我的活动将被解雇，但是
producer my observer will be invoked in
生产者，我的观察者将在
a different thread in an icing fashion
锦上添花
in a focusing fashion so that's
以专注的方式
something which is new in CI - and you
CI中的新功能-而您
see that when we are firing an event
看到当我们触发一个事件时
what we get in return is a completion
我们得到的回报是完成
stage so that as it came in that we can
舞台，以便它可以进入
combine the completion stage that we
结合我们完成的阶段
have discussed with jax-rs
与jax-rs讨论过
before with that completion stage object
在那个完成阶段对象之前
as well so that was a key dealing
同样，这也是关键
between the two API
两个API之间
now you have the ability to pass an
现在您可以通过
executor services so that's something
执行器服务，这就是
that is done when you fire when you fire
当你开火的时候就完成了
the event basically when you are when
该事件基本上是您何时
you are saying that you you want to
你是说你想
execute something as synchronously and
同步执行
do not provide an executor service it
不提供执行服务
will get invoked in fact in in a common
实际上会在一个共同的地方被调用
fog during pool of the Java 8 virtual
Java 8虚拟池期间出现雾
machine but you also have the
机器，但你也有
possibility to pass an executor as a
通过遗嘱执行人的可能性
parameter to make sure that your tasks
参数以确保您的任务
are going to be executed in that
将要执行
executor and this is especially useful
执行器，这特别有用
in the in your CDI world where for
在您的CDI世界中
instance you have a system that is going
实例你有一个正在运行的系统
to fire an event and this event is
触发一个事件，这个事件是
supposed to update some kind of swing
应该更新某种摇摆
panel or jfif xpanel or if you're in the
面板或jfif xpanel，或者如果您位于
Android space some kind of human
Android空间有点人类
interface panel and you know that in
界面面板，您知道
order to update this this kind of
为了更新这种
component of graphical component use a
图形组件的组件使用
graphical interfaces component and
图形界面组件和
properly you need to execute that code
正确地，您需要执行该代码
in a special thread in a special
在特殊的线程中
executor so you can pass an executor as
遗嘱执行人，因此您可以将遗嘱执行人作为
a parameter here and this is really
这里的参数，这真的
mandatory when you want to do that for
当您想要这样做时必须
instance swing utilities comic-con
实例swing实用程序comic-con
invoke later is an implementation of the
稍后调用是
executor interface might look quite odd
执行程序界面可能看起来很奇怪
but it is the case and you can pass that
但是确实如此，您可以通过
to make sure that this payload is going
确保此有效载荷正在运行
to trigger the updating of a swing panel
触发旋转面板的更新
for instance in the right in the right
例如在右边的右边
thread this is why it has been added in
线程，这就是为什么它被添加到
in CDI too and I think it's time to wrap
也可以在CDI中使用，我认为是时候打包了
up there we go so wrap up time right on
到那边去，这样结束时间
time
时间
unbelievable so today we have discussed
令人难以置信，所以今天我们讨论了
about the Jax rs21 API and the CDI into
关于Jax rs21 API和CDI到
API those API are part of a larger
这些API是较大型API的一部分
effort that is Java 8 which was just
Java 8的努力
finalized 12 days ago 21 of September
定于12天前九月21日
they are quite not well next to that
他们旁边的人不太好
there are quite some nice turf Engine
有一些不错的草皮引擎
Java yet like a support force hep-2 the
Java还像支持力量hep-2一样
servlet API support for Jason B in some
某些方面对Jason B的servlet API支持
of our codes we have used the Jason B
我们的代码中，我们使用了Jason B
API that allows us to easily and
API，使我们能够轻松地
Marshall and Marshall Java object and
Marshall和Marshall Java对象以及
JSON document and so on and so on so the
JSON文档等，依此类推
nice thing about most of those api is
关于这些API的大部分优点是
that they can obviously are part of the
他们显然可以成为
java platform and they can also be used
Java平台，也可以使用
outside of the java platform and that's
在Java平台之外，那就是
basically what we have done today the
基本上我们今天所做的
only thing is that if you are using the
唯一的事情是，如果您正在使用
completion stage within the java
Java中的完成阶段
platform you need to pass manage
您需要通过管理的平台
executor services because the the
执行服务，因为
container has to basically manage all
容器必须基本管理所有
the thread that will that you that will
那个你会的线程
be used so with that we have like two
被用来使我们有两个
minutes for questions
提问时间
so yes sir
是的，先生
yeah Jack's arrest you can use it on top
是的，杰克的逮捕，你可以在上面用它
of Java see that's not what we have been
Java的人看到那不是我们一直在做的
doing here so Jack's arrest Jason B
这样做是为了让杰克逮捕杰森B
servlet JSON P cgi-bin validation GSF is
Servlet JSON P cgi-bin验证GSF为
kind of tricky and secure security is
一种棘手和安全的安全性是
clearly the only API which is Java only
显然，只有Java的唯一API
so yeah yeah yeah and forgot to mention
所以，是的，忘了提及
that the compression stage API which is
压缩阶段的API是
basically the core of our talk today is
基本上我们今天谈话的核心是
Java C yeah yeah yes
Java C是是是
add some repeat the question
添加一些重复问题
yes I'll repeat okay sorry I'll repeat
是的，我会重复，好的，抱歉，我会重复
the question it was about the fact that
问题是关于以下事实
when you reach on a completion stage in
当您到达完成阶段
this jax-rs method you want to make sure
您要确保此jax-rs方法
that it is still executed in an
它仍然在
asynchronous fashion right okay so the
异步时尚好吗，所以
answer is in fact by essence the the
实际上，答案是
task wrapped in a completion stage is
完成阶段完成的任务是
executed in a thread either of the
在一个线程中执行
executor service you've passed as a
您已通过的执行人服务
parameter because you can pass an
参数，因为您可以传递
executor as a parameter when you create
创建时将执行程序作为参数
the task or when you call the then apply
任务或当您致电然后申请
then except then compose etcetera right
然后除了然后撰写等等
or in the comment for example of your of
或在评论中，例如您的
your Java 8 virtual machine okay so this
您的Java 8虚拟机就可以了
is guarantee because this is how the
是保证的，因为这就是
Java AC 8 completion stage completable
Java AC 8完成阶段可完成
future stuff works now well at this
将来的东西现在可以很好地工作了
given point you need to have the result
给定点，你需要得到结果
of that right and you you have to wait
的权利，你必须等待
for the result to get it so this has to
为了得到它的结果，所以这必须
be made synchronously okay you can all
被同步制作好了，你们都可以
only provide the result to the to the to
仅将结果提供给
the client once this result is available
此结果一经发布，客户端
so at some point you will fall back on
所以在某个时候你会退缩
on some kind of synchronous call but
在某种同步呼叫上
this synchronous call is triggered a
触发此同步呼叫
synchronously by the API itself there is
通过API本身同步
it's triggered one the result is
它触发了一个，结果是
available you do not have to wait
可用，您不必等待
yourself this isn't old by the API I
你自己，这对API来说还不算老
don't know if it answers your question
不知道它是否回答了你的问题
yeah okay thank you
是的，谢谢
any other questions
还有其他问题吗
come on don't be shy
来吧别害羞
well then we will give you one minute
好吧，我们会给你一分钟
back so we would like to thank you for
返回，所以我们要感谢你
our coming here we hope you enjoy it
我们来到这里，希望您喜欢
and please make sure to leave feedback
并且请确保留下反馈
when you leave the room thank you
当你离开房间的时候谢谢
[Applause]
[掌声]